ontrac.com 2019-12-29

# OnTrac Shipping - Privacy Policy

## 

The OnTrac Privacy Policy was updated on and is effective as of October 27, 2008.

**Protection of Customer Information**

This Privacy Policy describes the personally identifiable information that OnTrac ("OnTrac," "we," or "us") collects in the United States through our website located at http://www.ontrac.com (the "Site") and how we use that information. Your privacy is important to us. If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or our practices regarding your personally identifiable information, please contact us at [webcustomerservice@ontrac.com](mailto:webcustomerservice@ontrac.com).

**The Information That We Collect**

In order to better provide you with our numerous services, OnTrac collects two types of information about users of our Site: Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information. Our primary goal in collecting information from you is to provide you with a smooth, efficient, and customized experience while using our Site.

Personally Identifiable Information: Several areas of the Site ask for personal information such as Schedule a Pickup, Order Supplies Online, WebOnTrac Login, and Open a Free Account. It is completely optional for you to engage in these activities. If you elect to engage in these activities, however, we may ask that you provide us personal information, such as your first and last name, mailing address (including ZIP Code), email address, employer, telephone number and other personal identifying information.

Non-Personally Identifiable Information: This refers to information that does not by itself identify a specific individual. We may use browser cookies, web server log files, or other technologies to collect non-personally identifiable information in connection with your visit to the Site, such as the name of your internet service provider, the internet protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using, the type of browser software and operating system that you use, the date and time you access our Site, the website address, if any, from which you are linked directly to our Site, the website address, if any, to which you travel from our Site, and other similar traffic-related information.

If you contact us by email through the Site, we may keep a record of your contact information and correspondence, and we reserve the right to use your email address, and any information that you provide to us in your message, to respond thereto.

In order to respect the privacy of children online, the Site is not directed to children less than thirteen (13) years of age, and OnTrac does not knowingly collect, maintain or process personally identifiable information from such children.

**How We Use the Information We Gather**

We collect and store information about every package we handle so that we can efficiently provide the package delivery services demanded by our customers. We use information about our customers, their packages, and their shipping activity to provide or enhance the services we make available to our customers, communicate with our customers about additional services they may find of value, to bill you for those services you elect to use and to satisfy our legitimate business interests. It is our policy not to give, sell or otherwise distribute information collected through our Site to unaffiliated third parties. We reserve the right, however, to provide such information to our employees, contractors, agents, and designees to the extent necessary to enable them to perform certain Site-related services (e.g., web hosting, improve Site-related services and features, or maintenance services) on our behalf. In addition, we may provide personal information to government agencies as required by law or regulation.

**Changing or Deleting Personal Information**

You may access and correct any of your personal information and privacy preferences by contacting us at [webcustomerservice@ontrac.com](mailto:webcustomerservice@ontrac.com).

**Our Commitment to Security**

Providing security for all personally identifiable information associated with our users is very important to us. OnTrac has adopted commercially reasonable security measures to protect against loss and unauthorized access to all personally identifiable information which is under our control. We employ generally accepted information security techniques such as firewalls, access control procedures and cryptography for specific instances to appropriately protect confidential information from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company. Access to customer information is limited to those employees who have a legitimate business need for that information. Although we make reasonable efforts to limit access to our facilities and vehicles to authorized personnel, we are not responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of information that is printed and placed in plain view on a package or letter.

Unfortunately, no security system, or system of transmitting data over the Internet, can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Therefore, while we undertake commercially reasonable efforts to protect your personally identifiable information, we cannot guarantee the security of our servers, the means by which information is transmitted between your computer and OnTrac servers, or any information provided to us or to any third party through or in connection with the Site. You provide all such information entirely at your own risk.

**Retention of Customer Information**

We retain information, including personal information, about customers as necessary for business purposes and as required by government regulation. For example, we retain information about packages, including names and addresses, so that we can provide proof of delivery information and to process claim requests. We carefully dispose of records and delete information when retention periods expire.

**Links to Other Sites**

OnTrac provides links to external sites as a convenience to the user. The inclusion of any link does not imply OnTrac's endorsement of the external site company, its web site, or the products and services it promotes and sells. OnTrac is not and cannot be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. This Privacy Policy applies solely to the information which we collect through this Site. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of all destination websites which you visit.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a series of data characters that, when programmed into a web site, is placed by the web server into the browser's application folder on your computer. Once placed onto your machine, the cookie will allow the web site to "recognize" you as a unique individual.

Cookies can make use of the web easier by saving and administering status, application, preferences and other user information. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies but users can change the setting to refuse cookies or to be alerted when cookies are being sent. For instructions on how to change cookie settings, look in the Help menu on your Internet browser.

We use cookies (sometimes in conjunction with other technology) (i) to keep track of and administer customer status, preferences, business information and other information provided by a user, (ii) for security purposes, and (iii) to understand visitor usage of the Site on an anonymous basis.

******Comments and Unsolicited Ideas**

OnTrac or any of its employees do not accept or consider unsolicited ideas, including ideas for new promotions, new or improved technologies, product enhancements, processes, materials, marketing plans or new service names. Please do not submit any unsolicited ideas, original creative artwork, suggestions or other works (“submissions”) in any form to OnTrac or any of its employees. The sole purpose of this policy is to avoid potential misunderstandings or disputes when OnTrac services or marketing strategies might seem similar to ideas submitted to OnTrac. If, despite our request that you not send us your ideas, you still submit them, then regardless of what your letter says, the following terms shall apply to your submissions.

**Idea Submissions**  
You agree that: (1) your submissions and their contents will automatically become the property of OnTrac, without any compensation to you; (2) OnTrac may use or redistribute the submissions and their contents for any purpose and in any way; (3) there is no obligation for OnTrac to review the submission; and (4) there is no obligation to keep any submissions confidential.

**Service Comments**  
OnTrac does, however, welcome your comments. If you want to send us your comments, and we hope you do, we simply request that you send it to us using the form found on our Contact Us page. Please provide only specific comments on OnTrac services; do not include any ideas that OnTrac policy will not permit it to accept or consider. It’s just one more way that OnTrac can learn how to best satisfy your needs. Any comments you provide at this site shall be deemed to be non-confidential. OnTrac shall be free to use such information on an unrestricted basis.

**Revisions to Privacy Policy**

Electronic communication and the laws surrounding it are evolving rapidly. OnTrac reserves the right to update and revise this Privacy Policy at any time. You can determine if this Privacy Policy has been revised since your last visit by referring to the "Updated On" date at the top of this document. Your use of our Site constitutes your acceptance of the terms of the Privacy Policy as amended or revised by us, and you should therefore review this Privacy Policy regularly to insure you are aware of its terms.
